<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), Division of Watershed Management (DWM)</origin><pubdate>20000405</pubdate><title>Watershed Management Areas in New Jersey, Edition 200901 (Govt_admin_WMA_bnd)</title><edition>200901</edition><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Trenton, NJ</pubplace><publish>NJ Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP)</publish></pubinfo><onlink>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/listall.html</onlink><onlink>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>The depwmas data is a simplified version of dephuc14 data. The dephuc14 is NJDEP's version of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) hydrologic-unit-code basins that delineates the extent of the DEP watershed management regions and areas to be used for the statewide watershed initiative. Both the depwmas and dephuc14 data comprise the Watershed Base Maps for New Jersey.  Also, both were created from the USGS HUC14  by replacing the state boundary included with the USGS version with the DEP state and county border data(stco). The data was produced to address data-processing problems arising from combining the USGS huc14  with NJDEP GIS data due to the use of conflicting state boundaries.</abstract><purpose>Polygon and line coverage of watershed regions and watershed management areas (WMAS) proposed by the NJDEP for watershed characterization and assessment.  Includes an polygon item field for the names of the WMAS and line item filed for State and WMA boundaries.</purpose></descript><timeperd><current>publication date</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>200901</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>
-75.592927</westbc><eastbc>
-73.859684</eastbc><northbc>
41.357565</northbc><southbc>
38.849332</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>boundaries</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>none</themekt><themekey>Watersheds</themekey><themekey>water</themekey><themekey>watershed region</themekey><themekey>watershed management area</themekey><themekey>hydrologic-unit codes</themekey><themekey>hydrologic units</themekey><themekey>huc14</themekey><themekey>hucdiv</themekey><themekey>environmental protection</themekey><themekey>water management</themekey><themekey>dephuc14</themekey></theme><place><placekt>USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</placekt><placekey>New Jersey</placekey><placekey>State of</placekey><placekey>Arthur Kill</placekey><placekey>Barnegat</placekey><placekey>Cape May</placekey><placekey>Central Delaware</placekey><placekey>Crosswicks</placekey><placekey>Great Egg Harbor</placekey><placekey>Hackensack</placekey><placekey>Lower Delaware</placekey><placekey>Lower Passaic</placekey><placekey>Lower Raritan</placekey><placekey>Middle Passaic</placekey><placekey>Millstone</placekey><placekey>Monmouth</placekey><placekey>Mullica</placekey><placekey>Pascack</placekey><placekey>Pompton</placekey><placekey>Rancocas</placekey><placekey>Upper Delaware</placekey><placekey>Upper Passaic</placekey><placekey>Wallkill</placekey></place><theme><themekt>User</themekt><themekey>Govt_admin_WMA_bnd</themekey><themekey>WMA</themekey></theme></keywords><accconst>In most cases, a downloadable shapefile (.zip) version of this layer is also available. Information to download the shapefile can be found in the Distribution Section of this metadata record. This data layer is shown in the NJDEP's NJ-GeoWeb mapping application accessable through the Online Linkage: http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</accconst><useconst>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP)

Data Distribution Agreement

I.     Description of Data to be Provided.

The data provided herein are distributed subject to the following conditions and restrictions.

SUBJECT DATA LAYERS

For all data contained herein, NJDEP makes no representations of any kind, including, but not limited to, the warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular use, nor are any such warranties to be implied with respect to the digital data layers furnished hereunder.  NJDEP assumes no responsibility to maintain them in any manner or form.

II.    Terms of Agreement

1.      Digital data received from the NJDEP are to be used solely for internal purposes in the conduct of daily affairs.

2.     The data are provided, as is, without warranty of any kind and the user is responsible for understanding the accuracy limitations of all digital data layers provided herein, as documented in the accompanying cross-reference files (see Section 1.14  CROSS-REFERENCE).  Any reproduction or manipulation of the above data must ensure that the coordinate reference system remains intact.

3.     Digital data received from the NJDEP may not be reproduced or redistributed for use by anyone without first obtaining written permission from the NJDEP.  This clause is not intended to restrict distribution of printed mapped information produced from the digital data.

4.     Any maps, publications, reports, or other documents produced as a result of this project that utilize NJDEP digital data will credit the NJDEP's Geographic Information System (GIS) as the source of the data with the following credit/disclaimer:

"This (map/publication/report) was developed using New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection  Geographic Information System digital data, but this secondary product has not been verified by NJDEP and is not state-authorized."

5.     Users shall require any independent contractor, hired to undertake work that will utilize digital data obtained from the NJDEP, to agree not to use, reproduce, or redistribute NJDEP GIS data for any purpose other than the specified contractual work.  All copies of NJDEP GIS data utilized by an independent contractor will be required to be returned to the original user at the close of such contractual work.

Users hereby agree to abide by the use and reproduction conditions specified above and agree to hold any independent contractor to the same terms.  By using data provided herein, the user acknowledges that terms and conditions have been read and that the user is bound by these criteria.</useconst><browse><browsen>http://www.state.nj.us/dep/gis/digidownload/images/statewide/depwmas.gif</browsen><browsed>snapshot image of the DEP's Watershed Management Areas</browsed><browset>GIF</browset></browse><native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.6.1500</native><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), Division of Watershed Management (DWM)</cntorg><cntper>Steven Jacobus</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Section Chief</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>P.O. Box 418</address><city>Trenton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08625-0418</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>609-984-6888</cntvoice><cntfax>609-984-6505</cntfax><cntemail>Steven.Jacobus@dep.state.nj.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>Depwmas was produced by reselecting and labeling arcs corresponding to the proposed NJDEP watershed management area and regions from the dephuc14 coverage.  Polygon label were added and attributed accordingly.</attraccr></attracc><logic>The dephuc14 and depwmas are polygon and line coverages reassembled from the USGS HUC14 coverage. The HUC14 hydrologic unit boundaries, not including the state boundary, were delineated by the USGS from 1:24000 scale (7.5 minute) USGS topoquads. These data have been checked and verified by the NJDEP. Refer to huc14 metadata for more information regarding the data source. The state boundary lines included in these coverages are from the NJDEP digital data set stco. Refer to stco metadata for the origin and accuracy of these lines.</logic><complete>Updated 200403</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>From the Horizontal Positional Accuracy Report for dephuc14, the parent coverage: NJGS received sub-huc14 basins coverage from USGS-WRD in NAD27 UTM coordinates and began processing into Dephuc14 in NAD83 State Plane Feet coordinates. Projection resulted in a coverage that was shifted about 735 ft SSW in comparison to an earlier coverages. The reason for, and origin of this shift is unknown. Therefore, the projected coverage was manually transformed using an affine transformation to best fit the correct line positions based on a comparison to earlier version of the dephuc14 coverage.</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>No vertical attributes.</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>New Jersey Geological Survey</origin><pubdate>20000405</pubdate><title>dephuc14</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Trenton, NJ</pubplace><publish>NJGS</publish></pubinfo><othercit>Depwmas was produced by reselecting and labeling arcs corresponding to the NJDEP watershed management areas and regions from the dephuc14 coverage. Polygon labels were added and labeled accordingly. These coverages should be considered of true accuracy for the 1:24,000 scale (about 40 feet) based on stated accuracy's for the original data</othercit></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>24000</srcscale><typesrc>unknown</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20000405</caldate><time>unknown</time></sngdate></timeinfo><srccurr>publication date</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>huc14 subwatersheds</srccitea><srccontr>Digital file of subwatershed basins used to delineate Watershed Management Areas</srccontr></srcinfo><procstep><procdate>2000</procdate><procdesc>This data layer and the data layer from which depwmas was derived (dephuc14) are polygon and line coverages reassembled from the USGS HUC14 coverage. The HUC14 hydrologic unit boundaries, not including the state boundary, were delineated by the USGS from 1:24000 scale (7.5 minute) USGS topoquads. These data have been checked and verified by the NJDEP. Please refer to huc14 metadata for more information regarding the data source. The state boundary lines included in these coverages are from the NJDEP digital data set stco. Please refer to stco metadata for the origin and accuracy of these lines.

Off of New Jersey's Atlantic Ocean boundary the WMA boundaries (for WMAs# 12, 13, 14, 15, and 16) are set at 3 statue miles where a statue mile is 5,280 feet. This is not equivalent to the New Jersey state boundary. New Jersey's state boundary on the Atlantic Coast is 3 geographical miles offshore where 1 geographical mile is 6,087 feet. This is established by the 1953 Federal Submerged Lands Act.

DATA AUTOMATION AND ACCURACY

Depwmas was produced by reselecting and labeling arcs corresponding to the proposed NJDEP watershed management area and regions from the dephuc14 coverage. Polygon labels were added and labeled accordingly.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>200403</procdate><procdesc>Data was updated to reflect the official list for WMA names,  as follows:

WMA 1    Upper Delaware

WMA 2    Wallkill

WMA 3     Pompton, Pequannock, Wanaque, Ramapo

WMA 4     Lower Passaic and Saddle

WMA 5     Hackensack, Hudson, and Pascack

WMA 6     Upper and Mid Passaic, Whippany, and Rockaway

WMA 7     Arthur Kill

WMA 8     North &amp; South Branch Raritan

WMA 9     Lower Raritan, South River, and Lawrence

WMA 10   Millstone

WMA 11   Central Delaware

WMA 12   Monmouth

WMA 13   Barnegat Bay

WMA 14   Mullica

WMA 15   Great Egg Harbor

WMA 16   Cape May

WMA 17   Maurice, Salem, and Cohansey

WMA 18   Lower Delaware

WMA 19   Rancocas

WMA 20   Assiscunk, Crosswicks, Doctors</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>200901</procdate><procdesc>The Division of Watershed Management, in working with the various local watershed partners determined that the issues in Bayonne and the portion of Jersey City which were located within WMA 7 had more in common with WMA 5 then  WMA 7.  Therefore, the boundaries of WMA 5 and 7 were adjusted to move Bayonne and the portions of Jersey City that were in WMA 7 to WMA 5.</procdesc></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><sdtsterm><sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype><ptvctcnt>21</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><mapproj><mapprojn>Transverse Mercator</mapprojn><transmer><sfctrmer>0.999900</sfctrmer><longcm>-74.500000</longcm><latprjo>38.833333</latprjo><feast>492125.000000</feast><fnorth>0.000000</fnorth></transmer></mapproj><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.002048</absres><ordres>0.002048</ordres></coordrep><plandu>survey feet</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips><semiaxis>6378206</semiaxis><denflat>294.9786982</denflat></geodetic></horizsys><vertdef><altsys><altdatum>North American Vertical Datum of 1988</altdatum><altres>1.000000</altres><altunits>feet</altunits><altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc></altsys></vertdef></spref><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>WMA</enttypl><enttypd>Watershed Management Areas</enttypd><enttypds>NJDEP</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>DEPWMAS_</attrlabl><attrdef>DEP Watershed Management Area</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>unique value</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>DEPWMAS_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>DEP Watershed Management Identification Number</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>unique value</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>WMA</attrlabl><attrdef>WMA NUMBER</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Number assigned to the WMA Name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>WMA_NAME</attrlabl><attrdef>WMA Name</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>unique input</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>WREGION</attrlabl><attrdef>Water Region number</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Number assigned to the WR Name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>WR_NAME</attrlabl><attrdef>Water Region Name</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>unique value</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of feature</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed></eainfo><metainfo><metd>20090105</metd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc><metextns><onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>NJDEP/DWM</cntorg><cntper>Steven Jacobus</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Section Chief</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>P.O. Box 418</address><city>Trenton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08625-0418</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>609-984-6888</cntvoice><cntfax>609-984-6505</cntfax><cntemail>Steven.Jacobus@dep.state.nj.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><distinfo><distliab>This organization provides the geographic data "as is".  This organization makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of information contained in the geographic data.  Also, this organization makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of the product or its fitness for any particular purpose.  The burden for determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user.  Although these files have been processed successfully on computers at this organization, no warranty is made by this organization regarding the use of these data on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply any such warranty.  See also "Use Constraints" for additional distribution and/or data use requirements.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>DEP distributes ESRI .SHP and/or GDB. Some data may be NJ GeoWeb "display only" layers.</formname><formvern>latest version</formvern><filedec>WinZip</filedec></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/listall.html</networkr><networkr>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt><offoptn><offmedia>None</offmedia><recfmt>None</recfmt></offoptn></digtopt></digform><fees>None</fees><ordering>All available NJDEP public GIS data can be downloaded for free.  Some data shown in NJGeoWeb application may not yet be available for download due to various data or distribution issues.  Please email gisnet@dep.state.nj.us with any data distribution questions.</ordering></stdorder><custom>The NJDEP may distribute GIS data in a variety of formats, such as the ESRI shapefile and/or various versions of the file geodatabase format.  The data also may be available for viewing on various profiles of the NJ GeoWeb online mapping application.  

Note: Some older NJDEP data may not contain .prj files due to distribution procedures at that time. If download does not contain a .prj, please download from:

http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/njsp83.zip 

Please rename .prj to the name of the downloadable filename. (for example: If Head of Tides filename is HOT.shp, please rename .prj to HOT.prj).  This allows ESRI software to recognize the projection information.</custom><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NJDEP/OIRM/Bureau of GIS</cntorg><cntper>GIS Help Desk</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>401 East State Street</address><city>Trenton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08625</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>(609) 777-0672</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 292-7900</cntfax><cntemail>gisnet@dep.state.nj.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><Esri><ModDate>20120819</ModDate><ModTime>00154400</ModTime><CreaDate>20181127</CreaDate><CreaTime>12135800</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce></Esri></metadata>
